We will now begin the 57th
expedition beyond the walls!
Onward!
We believe that in the basement of
Eren Jaeger's Zhiganshina home,
there are answers about the Titans
that he himself doesn't have.
We will head there.
You new recruits will be here.
You'll be between the cart guard team
and the recon support team.
Your job will be to ride alongside the
spare horses and relay messages.
The Special Operations
Squad will be here.
Standing by in the center
of the last ranks.
It's the safest place in the formation.
Special ops will be here.
That's no Aberrant.
It's intelligent!
Like the Armored or Colossal
Titans, or Eren...
A human in the body of a Titan!
Its movements are much more
precise than the others' are!
Damn it.
I...
I underestimated it!
It protected its neck...
Damn it! I can't get away!
Jean!
Avenge the bastard who
rushed to his death!
It stopped?
That's the one...
That's the one that killed him!
He rushed to his death
on the right flank!
Avenge him!
We've bought enough time, right?
Let's get the hell away from it!
No... Why?
Is it
heading toward Eren?
Oh, my friend!
This is a victory for us!
Our fame starts here!
Oh, my friend!
Let us celebrate this victory for the next battle!
"I died for naught"
I won't let it end like that for you
until I am the last one standing
The enemy is cruel... We will kill...
The enemy is colossal... We will jump...
In our hands we hold blades of glory
and sing in the name of victory
We bear the wings of freedom on our backs
Swearing iron determination upon our hearts,
we slash apart the circle of idiocy
and soar through the sky
with our wings of freedom
Forest of Giant Trees: The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 2
How's your 3D Maneuver Gear looking, Armin?
It's okay...
The clasp released as intended,
so it seems it's not broken.
I see...
I'm glad to hear it.
But what do we do?
We only have one horse.
If Jean's horse comes back,
the three of us can move, but...
Damn it, why?
Reiner's horse returned, so why didn't mine?
We can't stay here any longer.
In the worst case, we'll have
to leave someone here...
But how would we decide who to leave?
Armin, since he's wounded?
Reiner, since he's big and would have
trouble riding with someone else?
Or should I run and try to find my horse?
Damn it!
Why the hell do I have to think about this?!
We all made it through that fight alive.
This isn't fair...
Armin...
Hey, Armin!
Are you still out of it?
Yeah, my head's still a bit fuzzy...
I see...
But we must decide.
It's a hard choice, but someone
will have to stay behind.
Wait!
First, let's fire a smoke round...
If the formation continued straight ahead,
the row 4-3 team should be nearby.
That's the signal for an emergency...
But I can't imagine they'll understand
our intentions just from that.
Armin, we can wait another three minutes.
By then, we must decide—
I'll stay.
But there's something I want
you to tell them for me...
Preferably to Commander Erwin alone—
No, Armin.
You should tell him yourself.
Looks like someone's here...
And with two horses!
That's...
Krista!
Is everyone okay?
That's my horse...
Whoa, whoa.
Calm down, Buchwald.
He ran toward me, terrified...
Did you engage the Titans?
Armin, what happened to you?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I think so.
I can't believe that smoke
round brought you here.
I was nearby, and I already had Jean's horse.
Even horses like you.
It seems you have a strange charisma.
You saved our lives.
But I'm so glad
that the worst didn't happen to you.
I really am glad.
God...
A goddess.
I want to marry her.
Well, we should rejoin the
formation as soon as possible.
Yeah, there should be orders to retreat.
To think we've been pushed back,
less than an hour out of the walls.
Things are even bleaker
than I'd imagined...
And for some reason,
it went in the opposite direction from
the vanguard command team...
It?
A green round?
Looks like they're continuing the operation,
only changing course...
What?
That wasn't a retreat command?
What is Commander Erwin thinking?
In theory, any soldier has
the authority to determine
when mission completion
is no longer possible.
Did command not see our
smoke round somehow?
Even if we don't know what's going on,
there's still only one thing for us to do...
Follow the order!
Smoke round.
Green.
Oluo, you fire it.
Roger.
For now, everything seems to be going fine.
But is it really?
We may already have casualties
on the front lines.
Reporting!
Message to pass along!
Right flank recon has been destroyed!
Our recon system is partially inoperative.
Pass this on, to the left.
Did you hear that, Petra?
Go.
Yes, Captain.
The right flank?!
I think that's where Armin is.
But Armin and the others should still
be in position, near the center.
The Titans can't have made it in that far...
A black round?
Aberrants?
Eren, you fire it.
R-Right!
What a mess.
We let it penetrate deep into our formation.
It's almost here...
The Titan.
Beneath those smoke rounds,
is there someone fighting?
Damn it...
Look over here.
You monster...
Now!
Three separate attacks at once...
You're pretty smart, but you can't
possibly protect all three targets!
Spine, Achilles tendon...
It doesn't matter!
Hit one, and we will slow it down...
Go!
Damn you for causing so many deaths!
We'll make you die a slow, painful death!
It jumped?
L-Let me go!
The most important thing is
to ensure they hear of this...
I must tell them what we're up against!
An Aberrant?!
It got in all the way here?
We'll take it out!
We can't let it penetrate any farther!
The right flank's been wiped out?
But we aren't withdrawing?
Why?!
No idea...
The Commander's orders...
Just relay the message to the left!
What's going on?
We keep heading east.
Our goal is supposed to
be south, to the old city.
Right now, our formation's
on a collision course.
Yeah.
You can see it...
The forest of giant trees!
Seems Titans passed through here.
There's nothing growing on the road.
We can bring the carts through, too.
Send word to the rear
that only the central cart guard
should enter the forest.
Yes, sir!
Excuse me, sir...
The center row appears to
be entering the forest,
but wouldn't the rest of
us collide with the forest?
We're going around.
Yes, sir!
Hey, what are we doing at this tourist spot?
We're totally off from both our original
destination and our return point.
I don't know...
I don't know, but the order came from
Commander Erwin, after all.
He must have a plan.
What kind of plan?
Are they planning to hold a welcome ceremony
for us new recruits at a tourist spot?
No, I don't think so.
That was a joke.
Anyway, that giant woman's following us.
No matter what his plan, we can't stay here.
The only thing I can imagine
is that we're passing through
on our way to somewhere else...
Everyone, halt!
All right. Listen up, recruits.
We will now make preparations
to launch a counterattack.
Draw your blades, and wait above in the trees.
If any Titans try to enter this forest,
stop them at all costs!
U-Um, Sir, what do you—
Shut up and follow orders!
Seriously?
What's going on?
H-Hey, it looks like only the center
line went into the woods.
What happened to the formation?
It's gone.
The forest blocks our advance,
so the left and right flanks
will have to skirt the forest.
We've lost our recon ability.
Why didn't we change course
to avoid this forest?
Did Commander Erwin read the map wrong?
I don't know...
Perhaps we tried too hard to avoid the threat
on the right flank and ended up here...
This is insane...
We've abandoned the original
mission to cache supplies.
And when we abandoned it,
we should've turned tail and run...
But instead, we're forging
ahead to a tourist trap.
And now, we're just standing here,
to stop any Titans that enter the woods?
Damn him for giving a crazy order.
He'll hear you...
And this no real explanation
thing is innovative, too.
Of course, I'm sure he has his own concerns...
What do you mean?
A commander deemed worthless
by his men in a critical situation
quite often succumbs to a
mysterious attack from behind.
I'm just saying it wouldn't surprise me.
Jean, so what are you going to do?
Don't be so serious...
This situation's got me a
bit worked up, that's all.
What am I going to do?
Obey my orders, and keep
Titans out of the forest.
You also think it's the right move, don't you?
Ah—
You look like you know something.
Well...
Five-meter class incoming!
Why bring the formation here?
What is Commander Erwin thinking?
No, that isn't what
we should think about.
The Female Titan is pursuing Eren.
And the Commander knows that.
Assume those two things,
and see what you can deduce...
Captain...
Captain Levi!
What?
Well...
We're in the middle of the woods!
If the center enters alone,
we won't know if Titans are approaching!
It seems something's approaching '
us from the right...
How are we supposed to dodge
the Titans or protect the carts?
Don't go on and on about the obvious...
We can't do that anymore, of course.
Th-Then why?
Look around, Eren...
At all these big-ass trees.
It's the perfect environment
for 3D Maneuver Gear.
And try to use that tiny brain of yours...
If you don't want to die, think.
Yes, sir!
I see.
I just can't keep up right now
because I'm still new.
He won't just tell me the answer.
I have to figure it out for myself.
I'm sure that's how they all learned to fight.
What the hell?
Seriously?
Damn it all... What the hell is going on here?
Wait!
Wait a minute... No one knows
what's really going on?
Maybe not even Captain Levi?
The Female Titan is after Eren...
If I'm right about that,
then there's only one reason to come here.
This is where Commander Erwin intends
to deal with the Female Titan...
Armin...
Our orders were to keep the
Titans out of the forest, right?
In other words...
There's no longer any reason to fight...
Right?
A black smoke round?
It's from directly behind us!
It's whatever was coming
toward us on the right.
Draw your blades.
If we see it, it'll only be for a second.
Go!
It's fast!
In these trees, there's no way to
foresee and evade its attacks!
It'll catch us!
Captain, let's switch to Maneuver Gear!
Captain!
You won't escape!
Reinforcements from the rear!
Captain, your orders?!
Let's go for it!
It's dangerous...
We should kill it!
I'll rip you apart!
Fool, you've run straight into hell.
You're chasing a group of master
Titan killers!
Captain Levi?
Captain!
Give us your orders.
At this rate, it will catch up with us!
We kill it here...
That's why we came to this forest!
Right, Captain?
Captain, your orders!
Everyone, cover your ears.
If we suppose that I am not me,
Can you say with certainty that you are you?
Will you be able to pick up after yourself
Once your sand-like shell breaks and your heart crumbles?
I could hear someone calling
But now my ears are just ringing
It's as if time has frozen
Now, wake up
I began to walk through a deep dark abyss
As swift as a gale, I escaped for my life
I felt like a living corpse
We break out of our walls
To reunite in worlds we've yet to map
The Female Titan approaches, continuing its unstoppable massacre.
With no choice but to flee, even as his comrades fall right before his eyes,
Eren is forced to make a decision.
Bite: The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 3